<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Spring - Category - Hi, Shihao</title>
        <link>http://miaoshihao.com/categories/spring/</link>
        <description>Spring - Category - Hi, Shihao</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>miao.shihaoo@gmail.com (Shihao Miao)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>miao.shihaoo@gmail.com (Shihao Miao)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:50:26 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://miaoshihao.com/categories/spring/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Spring MVC</title>
    <link>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/spring_mvc/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:50:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/spring_mvc/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Spring MVC Overview A Spring MVC is a Java framework used to build web applications by following the Model-View-Controller design pattern with the help of DispatcherServlet.
Model: A model contains object of the application. Controller: A controller contains the business logic of an application. View: A view is a webpage rendered by template engine like JSP, FreeMarker, Thymelead and etc. Front Controller: In Spring Web MVC, the Front Controller is DispatcherServlet, which manage the flow of the Spring MVC application.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Spring</title>
    <link>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/spring_overview/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:50:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/spring_overview/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Spring Spring Initializr The basic configuration of a ready-to-go spring project can be generated from below link.
https://start.spring.io
Spring and Spring boot Spring reduces the boilerplate code, and let developer focused on the code logic. Springboot is an extension of Spring that further eliminates the boilerplate configurations required for setting up a Spring application.
Spring Bean and Inversion of Control Spring bean represents objects which its dependencies is defined without actually creating them (Inversion of Control (IoC)).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Difference in Spring and Spring Boot</title>
    <link>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/springboot/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 22:50:21 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/springboot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Spring Boot is an extension of the Spring framework which eliminated the boilerplate configurations required for setting up a Spring application. This notes highlight the difference between Spring Boot and Spring.
Maven Dependencies Spring looks minimum dependencies required to create an web application.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10  &lt;dependency&gt; &lt;groupId&gt;org.springframework&lt;/groupId&gt; &lt;artifactId&gt;spring-web&lt;/artifactId&gt; &lt;version&gt;5.2.9.RELEASE&lt;/version&gt; &lt;/dependency&gt; &lt;dependency&gt; &lt;groupId&gt;org.springframework&lt;/groupId&gt; &lt;artifactId&gt;spring-webmvc&lt;/artifactId&gt; &lt;version&gt;5.2.9.RELEASE&lt;/version&gt; &lt;/dependency&gt;   Spring Boot requires only one dependency:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Spring Integration Notes(1) Overview </title>
    <link>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/spring_integration/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 22:50:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/spring_integration/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Spring Integration Basic Overview Spring Integration is an open source framework that designed to enable the development of integration solutions typical of event-driven architectures and messaging-centric architectures. It requires dependency spring intergration core, which could be downloaded from Maven Central.
1 2 3 4 5  &lt;dependency&gt; &lt;groupId&gt;org.springframework.integration&lt;/groupId&gt; &lt;artifactId&gt;spring-integration-core&lt;/artifactId&gt; &lt;version&gt;5.3.1.RELEASE&lt;/version&gt; &lt;/dependency&gt;   Spring integration framework consists three parts, namely message, message channel, and message endpoint. In general. a message is a unit of information that can be passed between different message endpoint through message channels.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Spring Notes 1: Spring Bean and IoC</title>
    <link>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/bean_ioc/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:30:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://miaoshihao.com/notes/computerscience/spring/bean_ioc/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[IoC container and Spring Bean IoC container and Spring bean can be treated as object factory and object respectively.
IoC Container IoC can be instantiated through below method.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8  ApplicationContext context = new ClassPathXmlApplicationContext(new String[] {&#34;services.xml&#34;, &#34;daos.xml&#34;}); // an ApplicationContext is also a BeanFactory (via inheritance) BeanFactory factory = context; // getBean() method can be used to test if context get required object Company company = context.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
